So, ladies and gentlemen, I want to make
a quick video on rules, regulations,
expectations on BuildWithMoves India.
So, we already have over 5,000 entries,
and we genuinely didn't expect that. I
was holding off on sending instructions
until the application slowed down, but
I'm super excited to finally kick this
off. So, in this video, we'll give you
the exact instructions with every detail
on what to build and how to submit. So,
I have a list here. I'm just going to
run you through everything, and I hope
we cover everything through this. So,
let's start with what to build. You can
pick one of the 10 public service
platforms on the screen. Now, if there
is a specific government website you're
really frustrated with that's outside of
this, and you submit that, that's also
okay, but your chances are a little bit
lower because if the team here who's
evaluating these projects, if we've not
had experience using that government
platform, then we might not understand
your solution as easily as the rest.
We're used to the rest. We know how they
work, which is why I recommend working
with these 10. But, remember, if you
make something exceptional, we'll see.
The second thing is we're expecting a
comprehensive proof of concept, which
means you rebuild it entirely. Mock the
data, the back end, and the accounts.
So, it's all mock back end data and
accounts. ChatGPT has something today
called sites, so even hosting is kind of
taken care of. We're not expecting this
to get crazy scale. This is just for us
to use, and that brings me to my next
step, which is provide login
credentials. So, we can actually get in
and test it. We only want to see it from
the consumer side, how end users like
you and me will use it, and not from the
admin side. The grading here is going to
be as a citizen using it. We assume you
built the admin side well. We aren't
really looking at it because anyway
during implementation, you'll need to
understand how it's currently
implemented. Next, focus on ideas over
code. Look, you can write code anything
today. And I think today what public
service websites in India need is new
ideas. So, today, remember that the
crazier ideas are harder to come by. The
actual implementation really depends on
how the public service website is
implemented. We'll do that later if your
projects are selected, but right now put
your energy into the interfaces,
interactions, try to build something
easier, something new. Uh if you want to
add in a map, you want to add in a tax
calculator, you want to make a chatbot
driven, just build out your best ideas.
Uh the more unique the idea, but still
useful to the end consumer, the better
it is. So, you could make a platform
that has all the bells and whistles, has
crazy 3D 3GS content going on, but that
might not actually be very valuable for
the end consumers. So, really think from
the end consumers who are busy, they're
frustrated with these platforms, they
don't have too much time, and they want
a solution quickly. Next, keep it small,
okay? Uh you can either go solo or bring
in a partner. You can bring in a maximum
of two people. The next is to get your
teammates registered. Your partner must
also be registered uh in the form that
we put out to compete. Send them the
link today. The next thing is the email
rule, and this is very critical. Your
email is your ID. The email you
registered with is your identity for
every form, result, and invite. And
there are no exceptions to this. If you
use a different email, lose access to
it, or your partner submits an
unregistered ID, unfortunately, with the
scale of results that we're getting in,
we can't really help you. Because
remember that at the end of the day, I'm
a content creator. Yes, we're on a
business, and all those people have work
to do. This is run mostly by the VM
content team, and uh we have a limited
team. So, if you lose access to your
account, it'll be very hard for us to
search. So, let me tell you how the
system will work. We have 5,000 people
who have already applied. We might have
many more, and we'll match everything up
by email. Now, let's go into the
submission process. The deadline for
round one closes exactly on August 28th
at 8:00 p.m. IST. So, form goes to your
registered emails. So, you have 7 days
to build. Now, remember that you can
still register for this even three or
four days later, but you have a shorter
period of time to then build. Because
28th is when your final submissions need
to go on that Google form. Now, I'll
tell you how you actually submit. You do
four things. Number one, you provide a
link. So, you provide a live public
link. It could be your ChatGPT website.
You want to host it on Vercel, you can
do it wherever you want. If it doesn't
open on a browser though, it doesn't
exist. So, we're not actually going to
download and use mobile apps. It has to
exist on a browser. The next thing we
need is either a Loom or an OBS or a
self-recorded video from you explaining
how you built the project and what it
is. This is broken down into 2 minutes.
2 minutes is your maximum time. The
first minute is you using the project as
a citizen and showcasing it. The second
minute is explaining how you built it.
Right? So, what is the decision you
took? Why do you do it a certain way?
This is for us to make sure that you had
some input in building it. You can do
this with your teammate. So, it's even
cooler if both of you get together and
make a video. It's good practice as well
to start making videos, especially in
2026. The third thing we need from you
is a text summary. Give us exactly 250
words what it is and why it's better
than the current solution. The last
thing we need from you is an email ID.
Okay? This email ID is not your email ID
because we already have that when you
submit the form, but the email ID of
your partner. And at the same time, your
partner has to put in your email ID.
This is the only way we can make sure
that you work together as a team. If you
have no partner, you can leave this
blank. But remember, without both
partners putting each other's email IDs,
there's a lot of potential for people to
game the system and we don't want to do
that. On August 28th, submissions close.
Now, I know you could be 10 minutes late
or 20 minutes late and and you know,
life always keeps us busy, but
unfortunately, we have to keep it fair
for everybody. At this scale, we have to
have a deadline and that deadline is
going to be what is stated on the screen
right now. So, between 28th of August
and 1st of September,
both my team and I, as well as the
OpenAI team, I've asked them for their
help in India, both these teams are
going to work together to go through the
submissions. Even with some of you going
in this with a team mindset, the maximum
number of projects we're going to cut
this down into is 250. Now, remember
that at the end of the day, you're being
judged by a bunch of people that are
looking through a lot of submissions.
So, remember that I might end up making
mistakes, my team might end up making
mistakes.
Uh there might be one or two good
projects that we miss. Statistically, at
the scale we're at, it's very likely. Uh
so, don't feel bad if you don't end up
making it.
It is not your fault. It's not because
you might not have engineered a great
solution. Uh we unfortunately can't sit
down and write a reason for every single
submission just because of the number of
submissions we're getting. But, at the
end of the day, we're trying our best.
Um we're giving benefit of the doubt. We
understand that when you're making a
POC, some things might be slightly off.
We understand all those things. So, we
are judging relative to the other
submissions that are coming in. And
we're going to take the top 250 ones
that we like. And everyone will have
their different tastes in the team. I
know that when we get rejected, we can
get a little bit angry, a little bit,
you know, you know, this was unfair or
that was this. Remember, a lot of the
time, humans make mistakes. At this
scale, there are going to be errors we
make. But, at the end of the day, this
is for a good cause. So, even if you
lose, know that in my mind, you are a
winner for even trying. But, everybody
will get an email. And you will know in
that email whether you made it or not.
The next piece is the fun piece. It's
the mentorship. The 250 final entrants
get one week in a WhatsApp group with
five different mentors to tighten the
project. So, I've actually gone to my
friends who I know have been engineers
for tens of years, people who worked at
really, really large companies, mentors
from Tech Twitter, credible developers,
and some people even from the OpenAI
team. Right? So, if you don't have
relationships with uh people in big
technology in India, this mentorship
will actually be really valuable for you
because you'll see how they think.
Right? Even if you don't end up winning,
you'll still see how they think. This
mentorship will be very valuable for
you. Now, they've agreed to do this for
free. So, there might be instances where
they might just have an insane amount of
work on some specific day, and they
might not be able to help. So, remember
that I can't physically hound them and
tell them, "Hey, you know, you have to
help these mentees, you know, 12 hours a
day or 15 hours a day." I can't do that.
But, at the end of the day, they're
coming out of their own goodwill.
They're coming out of their own
volition. So, yeah, I think they're
coming in with the right intentions, and
the idea is to help you shape a better
solution. So, you have 1 week to
actually improve on your solution. So,
we actually understand that in the first
week, the first submission that you put
in is going to be a little rough. But,
you have another week with a little bit
of mentorship where you can improve on
your solution. Because remember, we're
going to be demoing this, and lots of
people are going to see it. So, we want
to make sure it's as good as it can be.
The deadline for this is September 7th.
This is the round two submission. It's
the same format. You just put in updated
project. And remember, you have to use
the same email ID that you used in the
past. Your teammate has to use the same
email ID that they used in the past.
There is no way for us to verify
otherwise. If you use a new email ID,
we're just going to think it's some
different entrant and not let them in.
So, we're going to match the two and
only take on those projects. So, this is
why it's important you use the same
consistent email across both you as well
as your partner if you have a partner.
So, between September 8th and 12th,
we're going to announce the top 10. So,
after that period, we're then going to
announce the top 10. And remember that
if you made it to the top 10, you're
because of the number of submissions,
you're in the top
really the cream of the crop. And if you
do get rejected and don't make it,
remember that you're really competing
with some of the best projects out
there. And at the same time, mentors and
judges make mistakes. It's very human to
do. But, it's courageous that you even
got in the top 250. It's a big
achievement, and we'll have a page where
your name is out there, right? So, if
any tech companies in India are looking
to hire talent, you'll definitely be on
that page, and they'll definitely look
at you and your projects. So, you
actually have a proof of work, and we'll
have a page honoring the top 250. But,
if you're in the top 10,
congratulations. You're literally in the
absolute top, and you get to come on
September 12th and present live in
Bangalore to founders, creators, the
mentors that you've been working with,
and some of the government officials
we've been speaking to. Now, this is not
going to be a live-streamed event. It's
actually going to be a recorded event.
And we'll put out the video in a while,
and we will announce the winners the
same day both in location as well as
online. So, let me quickly get to the
prizes. The top 10, whoever makes it to
the top 10, gets a year of Codex Pro and
also a Codex micro. The top three get a
MacBook along with everything else that
we spoke about. And the top one will get
a trip to San Francisco subject to you,
of course, getting a visa. You know, as
a content creator, I can't really
control whether you get a visa or not,
but we'll try our best. Now, I just want
to quickly repeat the thing that I've
said multiple times throughout this
video, which is on rejection. I remember
I went to a hackathon when I was 20 or
21 and I got rejected, and I was super
bitter about it, right? But, I just
didn't understand the math. And in this
case, the math is pretty harsh. It's at
minimum 5,000 people who've already
applied, and only 10 get on stage. The
likely outcome is that you won't get
picked, but getting in the top 250 is
not impossible. You still have odds to
get there, and the mentorship will be
very useful. The network that you end up
building off that will be very useful.
And at the end of the day, some of your
ideas, the government might even see
some of those ideas. We might handpick
some of those ideas, keep it separately,
and get them to look at it. Now, I also
want to tell you what the goal with this
event is. Remember that all these
things, like the trip to San Francisco
or the Codex micros or the MacBook,
these are all incentives to get you to
participate. At the end of the day, the
goal is to create real dialogue between
the tech ecosystem in India, the content
ecosystem in India, and government
bodies. And they're more open than ever.
We have some soft confirmations already.
And imagine what a service you're doing
to your fellow citizen, which is all
your ideas, all your creativity. You're
giving the government clear POCs where
they can look at something and decide
whether that should be in the platform
or not. Now, we can't promise you that
the public service websites will
absolutely take all of these features
and put it on their platforms. Uh these
are legacy code bases. They may take
time. They might have dialogue with you.
They might get you involved part-time or
full-time. Uh these things may happen,
but there are no guarantees here because
ultimately we're dealing with millions
and millions of people. But after AI,
the ideas have become more important
than the implementation, and the ideas
here are the most valuable thing.
Anyway, that's it for me. I'm super
duper duper excited to see some of you
build cool solutions. And yeah, I can't
wait to see how the next 14 days goes
ahead.